Guide to the Bates Worldwide, Inc. Records, 1934-2005 and undated RL.00090
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials Series, 1981-2003 and undated; 43 boxes
  - Audiovisual Materials Added to Collection
    - Originals [CLOSED]
      - Bates USA
        - Hearn, David (Box AVO27)
          - OR-A-224. Address to Boca Raton summit, 2003 Mar. 10 (Box AVO27)
          - OR-A-225. Address to N.A. CCG summit, undated (Box AVO27)
        - History of Bates
          - OR-A-226. 1997 Dec. 12 (Box AVO27)
          - OR-A-227. 1997 Dec. 12 (Box AVO27)
        - Integrated Marketing Communications
          - OR-A-228. 1997 (Box AVO27)
            CD-ROM
        - Interview with Microsoft Executive
          - OR-A-229. 2000 (Box AVO27)
          - OR-A-230. 2000 (Box AVO27)
        - Knowledge Management, 2001 Nov. 19
          - OR-A-231. Big Brain (Box AVO27)
          - OR-A-232. Theme video (Box AVO27)
        - Levitt, Theodore
          - OR-A-233. Discussion about global marketing, 1998 Feb. 25 (Box AVO27)
        - Lobby reels
          - OR-A-234. All offices, 1996 Aug. 23 (Box AVO27)
          - OR-A-235. Interactive, 1998 Mar. 12 (Box AVO27)
        - Mars Corporation
          - OR-A-236. Powernet: the new agency with 40 years of continuity on the Mars business, 1994 (Box AVO27)
          - USP video, 1995 Feb. 2
            - OR-A-237. (Box AVO27)
            - OR-A-238. (Box AVO27)
        - Mixed Media Group
          - OR-A-239. Slate, master, 2000 Nov. 28 (Box AVO27)
        - Morris, Mark (Box AVO28)
          - OR-A-240. Get well video, 1998 Oct. 20 (Box AVO28)
          - OR-A-241. Paribas Bank speech, 1997 Apr. 28 (Box AVO28)
          - OR-A-242. Response to advisors for Merck and Co., 1998 Apr. 9 (Box AVO28)
          - OR-A-243. Video messages to Dr. Edwin Dorn and the Bcat team, 1995 May 30 (Box AVO28)
          - OR-A-244. Video shoot edited master, 2000 Sept. 26 (Box AVO28)
        - North American Board Meeting, 1997 Nov. 14
          - OR-A-245. (Box AVO28)
          - OR-A-246. (Box AVO28)
        - North American managers meeting
          - OR-A-247. 1996 Nov. 8 (Box AVO28)
        - Parker, Osbert
          - OR-A-248. 1996 May 1 (Box AVO28)
        - Pearson, Steve
          - OR-A-249. Appearance on Oprah, undated (Box AVO28)
        - Reeves, Rosser
          - Retrospective - AAF Hall of Fame Luncheon, 1994, Mar. 29
            - OR-A-250. (Box AVO28)
              - Digital preservation file, 0:06:10 (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0002, Video-file ORA250.mov)
            - OR-A-251. (Box AVO28)
            - OR-A-252. (Box AVO28)
            - OR-A-253. (Box AVO28)
          - OR-A-254. Testimonial, 2001 June 28 (Box AVO29)
            - Digital preservation file, 0:05:32 (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0002, Video-file ORA254.mov)
          - Tribute
            - OR-A-255. 1994 Mar. 24 (Box AVO29)
              - Digital preservation file, 0:06:52 (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0002, Video-file ORA255.mov)
            - OR-A-256. 1996 Nov. 26 (Box AVO29)
              - Digital preservation file, 0:05:33 (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0002, Video-file ORA256.mov)
            - OR-A-257. Undated (Box AVO29)
        - Rogers, Ken
          - OR-A-258. Historical reel, undated (Box AVO29)
        - Rutstein, [?]
          - OR-A-259. Good/bad oncologists, undated (Box AVO29)
        - Travel Tourism Research Association/Association of Marketing Executives, 1995 Apr. 19
          - OR-A-260. (Box AVO29)
          - OR-A-261. Master (Box AVO29)
        - Unique Selling Proposition (USP)
          - Advertising reels
            - OR-A-262. 1997 Oct. (Box AVO29)
            - OR-A-263. Master, 1997 Oct. 9 (Box AVO30)
            - OR-A-264. Show reel, 1996 Nov. (Box AVO30)
            - OR-A-265. Show reel, 1997 Apr. (Box AVO30)
          - OR-A-266. Bates USP Reel, 1997 July (Box AVO30)
          - Other reels
            - OR-A-267. 1997 June 13 (Box AVO30)
            - OR-A-268. For Bates Finance, 1997 June 13 (Box AVO30)
            - OR-A-269. Global Creative Services, undated (Box AVO30)
            - OR-A-270. Prepared for Canon, 1995 May 10 (Box AVO30)
            - OR-A-271. Reel with short intro, 1997 May 8 (Box AVO30)
            - OR-A-272. Worldwide, 1996 Nov. (Box AVO31)
          - OR-A-273. Presentation with John Fawcett and Les Stern, 1999 Apr. 8 (Box AVO31)
          - Traveling show (John Fawcett and Les Stern), 1997 Feb. 4
            - OR-A-274. General presentation (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-275. New York City Close-up, Part 1, unedited (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-276. New York City Close-up, Part 1, unedited (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-277. New York City Close-up, Part 2, unedited (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-278. New York City Close-up, Part 2, unedited (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-279. New York City Close-up, Part 3, unedited (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-280. New York City Close-up, Part 4, unedited (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-281. New York City Close-up, Part 5, unedited (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-282. North American region (Box AVO31)
            - OR-A-283. North American region dub (Box AVO32)
            - OR-A-284. Part 1 (Box AVO32)
            - OR-A-285. Part 1 (Box AVO32)
            - OR-A-286. Part 1 (Box AVO32)
            - OR-A-287. Part 1 (Box AVO32)
            - OR-A-288. Part 1, unedited (Box AVO32)
            - OR-A-289. Part 2 (Box AVO33)
            - OR-A-290. Part 2 (Box AVO33)
            - OR-A-291. Part 2 (Box AVO33)
            - OR-A-292. Part 2 (Box AVO33)
            - OR-A-293. Part 2, master (Box AVO33)
            - OR-A-294. Part 3 (Box AVO33)
            - OR-A-295. Part 3 (Box AVO33)
            - OR-A-296. Part 3 (Box AVO34)
            - OR-A-297. Part 3 (Box AVO34)
          - OR-A-298. Video, 1996 Apr. 18 (Box AVO34)
            Format: Betacam-NTSC
          - OR-A-299. Video, TELE-AN, 1995 Mar. 5 (Box AVO34)
        - Video tape clips for agency meeting, 1998 Sept. 29
          - OR-A-300. (Box AVO34)
          - OR-A-301. (Box AVO34)
          - OR-A-302. (Box AVO34)
        - Website
          - OR-A-303. Updated video, 2002 Dec. 6 (Box AVO34)
        - Westvaco
          - First-quarter address, 1997 Mar. 17
            - OR-A-304. (Box AVO34)
            - OR-A-305. (Box AVO34)
          - Fourth-quarter address, 1996 Dec. 13
            - OR-A-306. (Box AVO34)
            - OR-A-307. (Box AVO34)
        - Whiteford, Robert (UK) (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-308. Novaction interview, undated (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-309. Novaction interview, undated (Box AVO35)
        - Whitehead, Bill
          - OR-A-310. Presentation, Rising Signs, 1997 Dec. 3 (Box AVO35)
        - Worldwide management meeting
          - OR-A-311. Home videos, 1996 Apr. 26 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-312. Library copy, 1996 Mar. 18-22 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-313. Master, 1996 Mar. 18-22 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-314. Reel no. 01, 1996 Apr. 12 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-315. Reel no. 02, 1996 Apr. 12 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-316. Reel no. 03, 1996 Mar. 18 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-317. Reel no. 04, 1996 Mar. 18 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-318. Reel no. 05, 1996 Mar. 18-20 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-319. Reel no. 06, 1996 Mar. 18 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-320. Reel no. 07, 1996 Mar. 18 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-321. Reel no. 08, 1996 Mar. 19 (Box AVO35)
          - OR-A-322. Reel no. 09, 1996 Mar. 19 (Box AVO36)
          - OR-A-323. Reel no. 10, 1996 Mar. 18 (Box AVO36)
          - OR-A-324. Reel no. 11, 1996 Mar. 20 (Box AVO36)
          - OR-A-325. Reel no. 12, 1996 Mar. 20 (Box AVO36)
          - OR-A-326. Reel no. 13, 1996 Mar. 20 (Box AVO36)
          - OR-A-327. Reel no. 14, 1996 Mar. 20 (Box AVO36)
          - OR-A-328. Reel no. 15, 1996 Mar. 20 (Box AVO36)
      - Bates Worldwide
        - Advertising history
          - OR-A-329. 100 Years of Advertising in New York, 1996, Nov. 26 (Box AVO36)
          - OR-A-330. A History of Brand Building, 1995 July 14 (Box AVO36)
        - Bates Independence Day (Box AVO36)
        - OR-A-331. For internal education purposes only, 1997 Dec. 15 (Box AVO36)
        - OR-A-332. Bates Worldwide USP Showreel/Bates USA USP Traveling Show, 1997 June 5 (Box AVO36)
        - OR-A-333. Creative Standards Council video, 1996 Feb. 1 (Box AVO36)
        - OR-A-334. Global Creative Services, 1999 Oct. 18 (Box AVO37)
        - OR-A-335. Opening, 2002 Apr. (Box AVO37)
      - BSB/Campaign Palace (Australia)
        - OR-A-336. Management meeting, 1989 Mar. 30 (Box AVO37)
      - BSB Europe
        - OR-A-337. New Business Principles, undated (Box AVO37)
      - Cordiant Communications Group CCG)
        - OR-A-338. Annual Report, Global Creative Services, 1999 Jan. 28 (Box AVO37)
        - Board Meeting, 1999 May
          - OR-A-339. (Box AVO37)
          - OR-A-340. (Box AVO37)
        - Executive Committee Meeting, 1998 Sept. 14
          - OR-A-341. Creative services (Box AVO37)
          - OR-A-342. John Fawcett presentation (Box AVO38)
        - United Day, 2000 Oct. 12
          - OR-A-343. Dub master, tape 1 (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-344. Dub master, tape 2 (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-345. Edited master, full presentation (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-346. Part 1, revised short version (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-347. Part 2, 141 Communicator (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-348. Part 3, Morgen Walke (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-349. Part 4, design and branding (Box AVO38)
      - George Patterson Bates (Australia)
        - OR-A-350. USP Roadshow--TVC Compile, 1997 Oct. 1 (Box AVO38)
      - Saatchi & Saatchi
        - Bates/Saatchi European interviews, 1995 Jan. 6 (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-351. (Box AVO38)
          - OR-A-352. (Box AVO38)
        - OR-A-353. Key Emerging Markets--Russia, 1996 Mar. 14 (Box AVO38)
      - Ted Bates Advertising
        - OR-A-354. American Advertising Federation Hall of Fame Induction, 1988, May 26 (Box AVO38)
        - OR-A-355. Bates then and now, undated (Box AVO39)
        - OR-A-356. Benefits Presentation, 1985, July 24 (Box AVO39)
        - OR-A-357. Light, Larry, Think Global, Act Local, 1984 Jan. 28 (Box AVO41)
        - OR-A-358. Wycoski, R., Cannes 1989 speech, 1989 (Box AVO39)
    - Master Copies (Not for reference use)
      - MC-A-13. Brand Wheel, 1990 (Box AVM1)
        Format: BetacamSP. Source: OR-A-13. Date Created: 2006.
      - MC-A-101. Retrospective on Rosser Reeves, 1994 (Box AVM1)
        Format: BetacamSP. Source: OR-A-101. Date Created: 2007.
      - MC-A-148. Unique Selling Proposition (USP), 1988 (Box AVM1)
        Format: BetacamSP. Source: OR-A-148. Date Created: 2007.
      - MC-A-171. Unique Selling Proposition (USP), long version, 1995 (Box AVM1)
        Format: BetacamSP. Source: OR-A-171. Date Created: 2007.
      - MC-A-196. Ted Bates AAF Hall of Fame Induction, 1997 (Box AVM1)
        Format: BetacamSP. Source: OR-A-196. Date Created: 2007.
      - MC-A-226. History of Bates, 1997 (Box AVM1)
        Format: BetacamSP. Source: OR-A-226. Date Created: 2007.
      - MC-A-254. Rosser Reeves Testimonial, 2001 (Box AVM1)
        Format: BetacamSP. Source: OR-A-254. Date Created: 2007.
    - Use Copies
      - UC-A-13. Brand Wheel, 1990 (Box AVU1)
        Format: DVD. Source: OR-A-13. Date created: 2006.
      - UC-A-101. Retrospective on Rosser Reeves, 1994 (Box AVU1)
        Format: DVD. Source: OR-A-101. Date Created: 2007.
      - UC-A-148. Unique Selling Proposition (USP), 1988 (Box AVU1)
        Format: DVD. Source: OR-A-148. Date Created: 2007.
      - UC-A-171. Unique Selling Proposition (USP), long version, 1995 (Box AVU1)
        Format: DVD. Source: OR-A-171. Date Created: 2007.
      - UC-A-196. Ted Bates AAF Hall of Fame Induction, 1997 (Box AVU1)
        Format: DVD. Source: OR-A-196. Date Created: 2007.
      - UC-A-226. History of Bates, 1997 (Box AVU1)
        Format: DVD. Source: OR-A-226. Date Created: 2007.
      - UC-A-254. Rosser Reeves Testimonial, 2001 (Box AVU1)
        Format: DVD. Source: OR-A-254. Date Created: 2007.
- Electronic Records Series, 1987-2005
  Series contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - Digital Advertisements, 1997; Approximately 15 files; 8 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0001, Disk RL00090-disk-005-012 and RL00090-disk-068-072)
  - Digital Audiovisual Materials, 1994 and 2003; 1 file; approximately 5 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0001, Disk RL00090-disk-067)
  - Digital Client Files, 1987-2005; Approximately 4500 files; 4.5 gigabytes. (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0001, Disk RL00090-disk-001-003, RL00090-disk-0023-0024, RL00090-disk-0028, RL00090-disk-030-038, and RL00090-disk-065-066)
  - Digital Projects, 1994-2003; Approximately 225 files; 500 megabytes. (Digital-materials RL00090-SET-0001, Disk RL0090-disk-004, RL0090-disk-016-021, RL0090-disk-025-026,)